Rizha Musthafa

+6282213141987 (Mobile) - (Home)

rizha.musthafa@gmail.com

RESUME SUMMARY		
Latest Position	Supervisor	4
Years(s) of Work Experience	6 years	1
Latest Job Function	Software Enginer	
Latest Industry Sector	Information Technology	-
Latest Career Level	Senior	
Highest Education Attained	Diploma	
EXECUTIVE SUMMARY		

I like learning. Like sharks, programmers die if they stop moving. Because technology changes so fast, being a computer scientist means that "school" never stops. Even though I've been coding for years, I must constantly read programming books, follow blogs, and so on. There's no coasting!

I like play music instrument, which is very similar to programming. Both the musician and the programmer are obsessed with arts, obsessed with out of the box rules, obsessed with seeing how far they can push those rules, and obsessed with expressiveness.

i like building things which people enjoy it. It's amazing to type up some code, press a button, and suddenly hundred or even thousands of people are playing with it.

I like research, Programming tends to involve much googling and reading through documentation.

One of my favorite things about being Computer Scientist, the satisfaction of building something, and I get to learn about the kind of mistakes I make, to improve for the future.

SKILLS

Been Involved With:

Technology: E-Commerce, Online Classified, Daily Deal, Online Travel Agent, Telco System, Global Positioning System, Big Data, Payment Gateway, Online Game Payment, E-Procurement, ERP, CRM, SMS Gateway, Crawler, High Availability Server.

Programing Language: Java, PHP, Python, C++, C, Javascript, Bash.

RDBMS: MySQL, Postgresql, Oracle, Percona, Firebird, MariaDB.

NoSQL: MongoDB.

Store Cache: Redis, Memcached.

Search Platform: Lucene, Sphinx, Apache Solr.

Web Framework:

(PHP): Zend, Codeigniter, CakePHP, Yii, Laravel, Phalcon.

(Python): Django, Flask.

GUI Programing:

(Python): TKinter, PyQT

Mobile:

(Python): Kivy Cross Platform mobile Apps.

(Java): Android.

Unit Test: Python Selenium.

Crawler: Python, Selenium, PhantomJS

Embeded System:

(Python): Rasberry PI, Adruino.

Operating System: Ubuntu, Centos, Redhat, Debian, Windows Server, Windows 7, OSX

Integrated Development Environtment: Eclipse, Netbeans, Jetbrain PyCharm,

PhpStorm, IntelliJ IDEA

Version Controll System: Git (Bitbucket, Github), SVN(Assembla), Team Foundation

Server, Mercurial

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT Go Online Destination (www.pegipegi.com)

Sep / 2014 – Present

Software Enginer

- Participate in high level strategy discussions with team, work in areas outside of our comfort zone, and work quickly to get things done.
- Discover and implement new solutions to make PegiPegi scalable and fast
- Worked with a modern dynamic language and framework in unix environment, Python Micro Framework (Bottle, Flask), PHP Framework (Codeigniter, Laravel).

- Tuning and provisioning PegiPegi infrastructure to handle daily API requests .
- Working with data storage, specifically with MySQL, MongoDB.

Wicell Technology

Feb / 2014 – Aug/2014

Software Enginer

Oversee projects and supervise the day-to-day operations of team, making sure everyone is pulling their weight, distributing the workload evenly and making sure motivation and performance levels are maintained.

Provide vital assistance in the development, delivery and management of technical projects across multiple channels. Tasks including: identifying requirements, coding and testing programs, maintaining, tuning and troubleshooting.

Enjoy the responsibility of implementing new technologies, techniques and processes, always looking to implement clean code, be instrumental in informing and implementing technical solutions to drive innovation and efficiency and be actively involved within the wider development community.

Iforce Consulting

May / 2013 - Feb/2014

System Analyst

- Develops solution by preparing and evaluating alternative workflow solutions.
- Defines application problem by conferring with clients; evaluating procedures and processes.
- Controls solution by establishing specifications; coordinating production with programmers.
- Validates results by testing programs.
- Ensures operation by training client personnel; providing support.
- Provides reference by writing documentation.
- Updates job knowledge trough Research by participating in educational opportunities; reading professional publications; maintaining personal networks; participating in professional organizations.
- Accomplishes information systems and organization mission by completing related results as needed.

PT TOKOBAGUS Mar / 2011 - Dec / 2012

Software Developer

* Develop Mobile Web applications as identified by supervisor and management through packaged and customized applications.

- * Maintain and enhance Mobile Web applications and all internal systems are integrated.
- * Perform complete testing of Mobile Web applications –unit and system, engaging users as necessary.

Dyviacom Mar / 2010 - Mar / 2011 - 2011

PHP Programmer

Handle portal website project on http://www.waytodeal.com

and deal-of-the-day website project on http://www.ogahrugi.com

System Administrator

Create Webserver with loadbalance, database server, clustering file storage and security system on unix operating system.

PT Street Directory

June / 2009 - Mar / 2010

R & D PHP Programer

www.streetdirectory.com
On Research and Development Team
Build Search engine for web crawling with clustering db concept to make searching fast with PHP JAVA lucene engine.

EDUCATION

2006 - 2009

Bina Sarana Informatika, Manajement Informatika (major: D3)

LANGUAGES

Spoken: English, Indonesia.

Written: English, Indonesia.